For the remaining videos in this lesson,
在接下来的视频中
we'll go back to the Pokemon creature dataset.
我们将重新采用精灵宝可梦数据集
Let's say that we're interested in looking at the pairwise relationships between
表格中最后 6 列是宝可梦的战斗统计数据
the six combat statistics for all pokemon as seen in the last six columns.
假设我们要探索这 6 个变量之间的两两关系
Rather than plot scatter plots one-by-one,
不用再一个一个绘制散点图
we can inspect them all simultaneously using a plot matrix.
我们可以使用图表矩阵 一次性画出所有变量之间的关系
This can be done with seaborn's PairGrid function.
这个可以通过 Seaborn 的 PairGrid 函数实现
First, we set up the data frame on the data parameter and
首先我们将数据集传入 data 参数
specify the variables of interest on the vars parameter.
将感兴趣的六个变量传入 vars 参数中
If vars is not specified,
如果没有指定 vars 参数
then all numeric variables in the data frame will be put into the plot.
会默认绘制出数据里的所有数值变量
Even with only six variables,
尽管只用了六个变量
you can see that a plot matrix can take a lot of space.
你可以看到这个图表矩阵还是很占位置的
Each row corresponds with the variable from hp through special defense.
每一行代表依次表示 hp 到 special-defense 变量
The columns are also arranged in the same way.
每列所代表的变量顺序也是一样的
Let's start filling in the matrix with plots.
现在让我们给这个矩阵填入图表
Since all of the variables are numeric,
因为所有的变量都是数值型的
let's put a scatter plot in each cell.
所以我们在每一个单元格里放入散点图
Using the map method like with a FacetGrid,
与 FacetGrid 类似 使用 map 方法
we can add in a scatter column.
添加对散点图的调用
You'll notice that every cell now includes a scatter plot,
你可以看到每个单元格里 都画上了散点图
including those on the diagonals.
包括对角线上的图形
These diagonals are just straight lines since the column and row variables match up.
但这些对角线上的图表只是一条直线 因为这些图表的行和列是同一个变量
Let's use the map_diag method to put histograms on the diagonal,
让我们用 map_diag 方法把直方图放在对角线上
and change map to map_offdiag to plot scatter plots only on the off-diagonal cells.
并且将 map 改为 map_offdiag 将散点图画在对角线之外的单元格上
Looking at this plot matrix,
让我们来看一下这个图表矩阵
we can see some stronger relationships between hp and attack,
我们可以看到 hp 和 attack 之间、attack 和 defense 之间
attack and defense, and special attack and special defense.
special-attack 和 special-defense 之间有着很强的相关性
Let's check this numerically by computing and
让我们再来看一下变量之间的相关系数
plotting the correlations in a correlation heatmap.
并把它们用热图画出来
The core function returns a matrix of
corr 函数返回一个包含
pairwise of correlations between our selected variables.
所选变量相互之间相关系数的矩阵
Putting this into the heatmap function produces our desired visualization.
把这个数据放入 heatmap 函数中就可以得到我们想要看到的热图
Let's add some parameters to the heatmap.
让我们在热图中加入一些参数
Reverse the color palette using cmap then add
通过 cmap 参数修改调色板
annotations to format the values with two decimal places.
通过 annot 参数使每个单元格显示出数值 保留两位小数
It looks like there's only one correlation that's negative between defense and speed.
看上去似乎只有 defense 和 speed 这两个变量之间是负相关的
Since it's essentially zero,
因为它约等于零
let's add a vmin argument to set the lower bound of the colormap to zero.
所以我们可以设置 vmin 参数将 colormap的下限值设为 0
The correlation heatmap supports the observations we made from the plot matrix.
这个相关系数热图符合我们从图表矩阵里得到的结果
We see that there are relatively high correlation values between hp and attack,
我们看到 hp 和 attack 之间、attack 和 defense 之间
attack and defense, and special attack and special defense.
以及 special-attack  和 special-defense 的相关性很高
But it looks like there's a surprisingly high correlation
但是 defense 和 special-defense 之间的相关性似乎
between defense and special defense.
出乎意料得高
Looking back on the plot matrix,
重新再去看图表矩阵
perhaps that outlier in the upper right is boosting the statistic.
有可能右上方的异常值把整体统计数据拉高了
That point would be worth further investigation in a deeper dive.
这个点值得进一步深入调查